{
    "id": "bb63951bf5504455a1534e94392b45e8",
    "title": "Definite And Indefinite Articles Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "48fdcf2b6950491bbcac45a7d24ed16a",
            "title": "Definite And Indefinite Articles",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Twelve inches make ………………. foot.",
                    "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the numerical sense of one.",
                    "answers": [
                        "the",
                        "a",
                        "No article is required"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "One evening ……………………. beggar came to my door.",
                    "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the vague sense of ‘a certain’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "a",
                        "the"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………….. student should obey her teacher.",
                    "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the sense of ‘any’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "A",
                        "The",
                        "No article is required"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "At last ……………………….. warrior in him was thoroughly aroused.",
                    "description": "The definite article ‘the’ is sometimes placed before a common noun to give it the meaning of an abstract noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "a",
                        "the",
                        "No article is required"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is ………………………. best book on elementary chemistry.",
                    "description": "The definite article ‘the’ is used with superlative adjectives.",
                    "answers": [
                        "a",
                        "the",
                        "No article is required"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "What kind of ……………………….. is it?",
                    "description": "Articles are omitted before common nouns used in their widest sense.",
                    "answers": [
                        "flower",
                        "the flower",
                        "a flower"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Newton was ……………………….. great scientist and philosopher.",
                    "description": "The indefinite article ‘a’ can be used in the numerical sense of ‘one’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "a",
                        "the",
                        "No article is required"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I cannot forget ……………………….. with which he treated me.",
                    "description": "An abstract noun may have the article ‘the’ when it is followed by an adjective or adjectival phrase.",
                    "answers": [
                        "kindness",
                        "a kindness",
                        "the kindness"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………… is the only animal that uses fire.",
                    "description": "When the noun man is used in the general sense, it does not take an article.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Man",
                        "The man",
                        "A man"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………. tenth chapter of this book is very interesting.",
                    "description": "The definite article ‘the’ is used with ordinal numbers.",
                    "answers": [
                        "The",
                        "A",
                        "No article is required"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. is its own reward.",
                    "description": "Articles are omitted before abstract nouns used in a general sense.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Virtue",
                        "A virtue",
                        "The virtue"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I learnt German at ……………………..",
                    "description": "No article is used when the reference is to the primary purpose of the nouns school, college, hospital, prison or church.",
                    "answers": [
                        "school",
                        "a school",
                        "the school"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}